Tercio de Melo

contact@tercio.com.br

Berlin - Germany

LONG STORY SHORT

I'm a Software Engineer with a strong background on cloud infrastructure and distributed systems with intensive data requirements. I've started my professional career building backend systems in the mobile gaming industry, handling traffic of millions of players at the unicorn Wildlife Studios. In the sequence I spent about an year as contractor stabilizing cloud infrastructure of growing companies in Silicon Valley and Brazil. Then I worked for three years in e-commerce, both being part of the launch of Amazon.com.br and building a serverless technology at the unicorn VTEX called VTEX IO. Then while I was working at the Data division of Nubank I and my wife decided that we should move to Berlin to build our family, which brought me to SumUp, where I'm focusing on the DataOps side of things, in a similar role to that I had taken at Nubank.

EDUCATION LANGUAGES

Universidade Federal de Campina Grande

Computer Science 2011 - 2016

University of Utah

Sandwitch Graduation, Computer Science 2013 - 2013

- Sponsored international student in Science Without Borders program
- Sponsors: Brazil's Capes and USA's Institute of International Education (IIE)
- Program duration: 2 semesters

EXPERIENCE

SumUp, Berlin

AUGUST 2021 - PRESENT

English:

German:

Portuguese: native

French: basic

fluent

basic

Senior DevOps Engineer

- Focus on DataOps with automation, monitoring, and design of reproduceable data environments
- Maintenance of BI platform infrastructure
- Planning and execution of services migration from legacy to new Infrastructures

Nubank, São Paulo

DECEMBER 2020 - JULY 2021

Senior Systems Engineer

- \bullet Working on cost reduction for data transfer between different cloud providers
- Working on enhancing granular access control for many different clearance levels

Loggi, São Paulo

JULY 2020 - OCTOBER 2020

Senior Site Reliabity Engineer

- Dev tool for managing services releases
- Services migration and mirroring between Azure and AWS
- CI/CD pipeline assemble for Blue-Green deployment in different infrastructures

VTEX, Rio de Janeiro

SEPTEMBER 2018 - JULY 2020

Senior Site Reliabity & Software Engineer

- Load testing platform on top of Kubernetes
- Automation of Kubernetes, IaC, Deployments with Rancher, Terraform, and CD/CD pipelines
- Edge traffic routing and management with Envoy Proxy, NGINX, AWS Cloudfront, AWS Lambda and AWS ALB/NLB
- In-house control planes for Envoy proxy
- Logs/messages/events routing, filtering, queuing with Fluentd, Kafka, Elasticsearch and Splunk
- Monitoring with Prometheus, Grafana and Splunk
- Tooling for infrastructure operations like rapid edge re-routing and launching new infrastructures in different cloud regions

Amazon, São Paulo

OCTOBER 2017 - AUGUST 2018

Software Development Engineer

- Built warehouse logistics and integration services
- Built Spark jobs for crunching numbers

TapInfluence, Remote contractor

FEBRUARY 2017 - OCTOBER 2017

Software Architect & DevOps Engineer

- Containerized services with Docker for better environment management
- Bugs cleanup workforce, testing environment restoration, and service stabilization
- Developed development tooling
- Developed backend features in Ruby on Rails
- Developed frontend features in Backbone.js and JavaScript components

DSL Lab @ UFCG, Campina Grande

AUGUST 2016 - DECEMBER 2016

Cloud Computing Engineer

- Technical leader of a team responsible for developing integration software between Lenovo LXCA and RedHat ManageIQ
- Developed Ruby client library for LXCA operation

Freelancer, Remote contractor

JULY 2016 - DECEMBER 2016

Full-Stack & DevOps Engineer

- Developed features and fixed bugs in client's products
- Containerized services for infrastructure automation in stateless deployments

Wildlife Studios, São Paulo

AUGUST 2015 - JUNE 2016

Full-Stack & DevOps Engineer

- Built a Node.js system for players progress persistence and synchronization between mobile devices
- Was part of the team that built a distributed game server based on Pomelo Framework
- Managed services in cloud VMs using AWS OpsWorks, Chef, Docker, PM2, and Kubernetes
- Extended Yahoo's Kafka Manager open-source service by implementing a feature of manual partition assignments in Kafka clusters

• Built iOS library for play test recording sessions

Software Developer Intern

FEBRUARY 2015 - JULY 2015

- Built Android library for collecting users events for analytics
- Built Android library for SSL certificate pinning
- Built a computational geometry classifier for racing tracks built by users on Bike Race Free mobile game
- Built development tools
- Built data scraping sytems

SPLab @ UFCG, Campina Grande

FEBRUARY 2014 - DECEMBER 2014

Embedded Software Developer

• Built C/C++/Java embedded systems for Ingenico credit cards terminals

SPLab @ UFCG, Campina Grande

JULY 2011 - OCTOBER 2012

Research Assistant

- Researched evolution of software architecture quality of by open source projects by running tests, crunching numbers, and reviewing scientific literature
- Researched software architectural metrics and refactoring suggestions automation by running tests, crunching numbers, and reviewing scientific literature